在之前的阅读中，我们已经形成了一个严格的概念
In previous readings, we've developed a rigorous notion
数据抽象，抽象数据类型，
of data abstraction, abstract data types,
通过创建具有以下特征的类型
by creating types that are characterized
通过他们的行动，而不是他们的代表。
by their operations, not by their representation.
对于抽象数据类型，抽象函数
For an abstract data type, the abstraction function
解释如何解释具体的销售代表
explains how to interpret a concrete rep
值作为抽象类型的值。
value as a value of the abstract type.
我们看到了抽象函数的选择
We saw how the choice of abstraction function
确定如何编写代码实现
determines how we write the code implementing
ADT的每个操作。
each of the ADT's operations.
在这篇文章中，我们回到
In this reading, we return to how
我们定义了数据类型中值相等的概念。
we define the notion of equality of values in a data type.
抽象函数实际上是
The abstraction function is actually
使我们能够清楚地定义
made us a way to cleanly define what the equality
在ADT上操作意味着。
operation means on an ADT.
现在出现在现实世界，物质世界，
Now popping out in the real world, the physical world,
每个物体都是不同的。
every object is distinct.
在某种程度上，即使是两片雪花
At some level, even two snowflakes
是不同的，即使区别只是
are different, even if the distinction is just
它们在太空中所占据的位置。
the position they occupy in space.
事实上，这不是真的
Actually, this isn't strictly true
所有的亚原子粒子，但是
of all subatomic particles, but it's
足够大的物体像雪花和棒球
true enough of large objects like snowflakes and baseballs
还有人。
and people.
我们有常识经验的东西。
Things we have common sense experience with.
所以两个物体永远不会
So two physical objects are never
彼此真正平等。
truly equal to one another.
它们只有相似的程度。
They only have degrees of similarity.
但是在人类语言的世界里，在数学的世界里，
But in the world of human language, in the world of math,
同一件事可以有多个名字。
you can have multiple names for the same thing.
所以很自然地会问
So it's natural to ask when two expressions represent
同样的东西，1加2，9的平方，
the same thing, 1 plus 2, squared of nine,
3个都是可选表达式
and 3 are all alternative expressions
为了同样的理想数学值。
for the same ideal mathematical value.
所以考虑到ADTs，正式的我们
So thinking about ADTs, formally we
可以从几个方面看待平等和ADT。
can regard equality and ADTs in several ways.
首先，使用抽象函数。
First, using an abstraction function.
所以请记住，抽象函数
So remember that an abstraction function
F从空间映射数据类型的具体实例
F maps concrete instances of a data type from the space
它们对应的抽象值。
R to their corresponding abstract values in A.
所以用F来定义平等，
So to use F as a definition for equality,
当且仅当A的F等于B的F时，我们会说A等于B。
we would say A equals B if and only if F of A equals F of B.
换句话说，如果它们的抽象映射是
If, in other words, their abstract mappings are
同一个数学对象。
the same mathematical object.
第二种方法是使用关系。
Second way is using a relations.
所以数学上的等价是一种关系，
So an equivalence in math is a relation,
抽象数据类型的有序对的子集
E a subset of the ordered pairs of the abstract data type
它有三个属性。
T that has three properties.
首先，它必须是反射性的。
First, it has to be reflexive.
换句话说，对于数据类型中的所有值
In other words, for all the values in the data type
一定是真的，这对，T，T，是在那种关系中。
must be true that the pair, T, T, is in that relation.
它必须是对称的。
It must be symmetric.
如果TU在关系中，那么UT也在关系中。
If TU is in the relation, then UT is also in the relation.
它必须是可传递的。
And it must be transitive.
如果TU在关系中，UV在关系中，
If TU is in the relation, and UV is in the relation,
那么电视就是关系。
then TV is in the relation.
所以如果我们把E看作一个等号，
So if we think about E as an equal sign here,
这些规则你应该从普通数学中熟悉。
these rules should be familiar to you from ordinary math.
如果我们用E，这个等价关系
So if we use E, this equivalence relation
作为平等的定义，我们可以说a等于B
as a definition for equality, we would say that A equals B if
只有当这个关系包含有序对AB时。
and only if this relation contains the ordered pair AB.
现在这两个概念使用一个抽象函数，使用
Now these two notions using an abstraction function, using
一个关系，是等价的。
a relation, are equivalent.
等价关系产生抽象函数
An equivalence relation induces an abstraction function
因为关系划分T所以F只是映射每个元素
because the relation partitions T so F just maps each element
到它的分区类。
to its partitioned class.
抽象函数引起的关系
The relation induced by an abstraction function
是一个等价关系。
is an equivalence relation.
你可以自己检查一下这三个属性是否有效。
You can check for yourself that those three properties hold.
第三种方法是平等
Now a third way we can talk about equality
在抽象值之间
between abstract values is in terms
一些局外人，比如抽象数据的客户
of what some outsider, like a client of the abstract data
打字，可以观察他们。
type, can observe about them.
我们可以说两个物体在不能相等时是相等的
We can say that two objects are equal when they cannot be
以观察为特点，当我们能
distinguished by observation, when every operation we can
应用为两个对象生成相同的结果。
apply produces the same result for both objects.
所以考虑集合表达式，1，2和2，1。
So consider the set expressions, 1, 2 and 2, 1.
使用可用于集合的观察者操作，
Using the observer operations that are available for sets,
例如基数，集合的大小和成员，
such as cardinality, the size of the set, and membership,
元素是否是集合的成员，
whether an element is a member of the set,
这些表达式，1，2和2，1，
these expressions, 1, 2 and 2, 1,
实际上是无法区分的。
are actually indistinguishable.
集合的基数是2。
The cardinality of the set is 2.
这个集合的基数也是2。
The cardinality of this set is also 2.
1是1，2的成员。
1 is a member of 1, 2.
1也是2，1的成员。
1 is also member of 2, 1.
同样需要2个。
want Likewise for 2.
你可以尝试的任何其他价值
Any other value that you might try
不是1，2的成员，也不是2，1的成员。
is not a member of 1, 2 and not a member of 2, 1.
所以对于这些操作，基数和成员，
So for both of these operations, cardinality and membership,
这两个设定值无法区分。
these two set values are indistinguishable.
现在就Java中的抽象数据类型而言，
Now in terms of abstract data types in Java,
观察意味着调用对象上的操作。
observation means calling operations on the objects.
所以两个Java对象是相等的，只要它们不能
So two Java objects are equal if and only if they cannot be
通过调用抽象数据的任何操作来区分
distinguished by calling any operations of the abstract data
键入。
type.
这里有一个不可变ADT的简单例子
So here's a simple example of an immutable ADT
我们将在今天的阅读中用到。
that we're going to use throughout today's reading.
这个ADT应该代表一段时间。
It's an ADT that's supposed to represent a duration of time.
它有一个创建者，需要几分钟，然后
It has a creator that takes a number of minutes, then
数秒并创建持续时间。
a number of seconds and creates a duration.
它有一个观察者返回长度
And it has an observer that returns the length
以秒为单位的持续时间。
of the duration in seconds.
我们有一个销售代表负责记录
And we have a rep that stores the minutes and seconds
持续时间所代表的。
that the duration represents.
一个代表不变量说
And a rep invariant that says that those
必须大于或等于0。
have to be greater than or equal to 0.
以及一个将这两个值关联起来的抽象函数
And an abstraction function that relates those two values
抽象的价值，即时间跨度的概念
to the abstract value which is the notion of a span of time
通过说它对应于一段时间，
by saying that it corresponds to a span of time,
它是分，分，秒，长。
which is min, minutes, and sec, seconds, long.
既然如此，既然我们已经讨论过
So given that, given what we've talked about for the ways
我们可以在抽象数据类型中考虑平等，
that we can regard equality in abstract data types,
哪些值应该被认为是相等的？
which of these values should be considered equal?
所以让我们考虑一下，两个抽象函数
So let's think in terms, both the abstraction function
定义和观察定义，
definition and the observational definition,
你会在练习中给出答案。
and you'll give your answer in the exercises.